tybit.com 2008-12-19

# tyBit® | Unified Search® | privacy policy

**tyBit, INC. PRIVACY POLICY**

tyBit, Inc. (“ **tyBit** ”) understands your concern regarding the personal information (“ **Information** ”) that you supply or which may be collected while you enjoy its search engine and other applications. This Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time (“ **Privacy Policy** ”), sets out the type of Information collected and the potential use of that Information. By utilizing tyBit’s search engine and other applications, you are accepting and agreeing to the practices described in this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use, and you consent to the use of your Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use. tyBit may change its practices at any time without notice and it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy from time to time. You agree that any changes made to this Privacy Policy will be effective as of the date posted on its website or other applications, as the case may be.    **  
**  
**Privacy Philosophies         **  
Although our business and search engine have unique services and offerings, they share a similar privacy philosophy. tyBit follows these privacy principles in our conduct in the collection, use, release and security of Information both online and offline: 

·         Providing you **_NOTICE_** of our information practices. 

·         Giving you **_CHOICES_** about how your data will be used. 

·         Providing you the opportunity to **_UPDATE or CORRECT_** your personal information. 

·         Using information **_SECURITY_** safeguards. 

·         Limiting the **_SHARING_** of your information. 

·         Committing to **_COMPLYING_** with applicable privacy requirements. 

·         Providing you with means to **_CONTACT US_** about privacy-related issues. 

**Our Technology and the Information We Collect          
**tyBit’s technology provides a method and program for its partners and advertisers (“ **Advertisers** ”) to distribute its marketing materials contained within the tyBit search engine and other applications to you while receiving valuable and accurate feedback on what you think is interesting.  We collect your name, electronic mail address and zip code when you install our technology onto your computer or mobile device.  Our technology enables us to determine (i) your geographic location from either the zip code that you provide to tyBit when installing tyBit’s search engine and/or other applications onto your computer or through your GPS of your mobile device; (ii) your age and income if you voluntarily submit it to tyBit; (iii) your search terms or interactive behavior with our search engine; (iv) your purchasing behavior; (v) your computer location through your unique computer IP address; (vi) source of the information sought by you during your search; and (vii) the age of your results data (collectively, the “ **Collected Information** ”).  

This type of technology, as described in greater detail below, is similar to that used by websites for the past several years.  In fact, when you visit a website and surf around, your click stream data, or mouse clicks, are being recorded by the web server.  We have essentially transferred a similar capability to our search engine and other applications and programmed them to send these recordings to a server.  The data is then available for analysis and reporting sorted by unique computers, rather than unique users.

**TCP-IP**   
In accordance to _Wikipedia_ , “[t]he Internet protocol suite is the set of communications protocols that implement the protocol stack on which the Internet and most commercial networks run. It has also been referred to as the TCP/IP protocol suite, which is named after two of the most important protocols in it: the Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and the Internet Protocol (IP), which were also the first two networking protocols defined.”  tyBit utilizes TCP-IP to communicate your Collected Information to tyBit.

**How We Use And Share Information**              
The Collected Information is used to generate reports from your use of our search engine and other applications, as well as the overall use of all of our Advertisers’ marketing campaigns distributed to you utilizing our technology.  tyBit also uses the Collected Information to create online communities that are based on their members’ common interests.  tyBit does not collect the Collected Information for any other purpose.     

tyBit discloses to its Advertisers the Collected Information.  Again, this data is then available for analysis and reporting sorted by unique computers, rather than unique users.  tyBit also discloses to its US and foreign subcontractors the Collected Information in order to provide tyBit related services to you.              

Since our Advertisers are also committed to high privacy standards, they agree to use the reports that we provide to it to deliver to you their advertisements based on your interests and demographics, and to evaluate the success of their search engine or other application marketing campaigns and will not share the reports with any other party.  For a better understanding of our Advertisers’ privacy standards, please visit their Privacy Policy when viewing their websites.  

From time to time, tyBit may be required to provide the Collected Information in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may release certain personal information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of others and ourselves. We may also release personal information in the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event.      

**If you are accessing our search engine or other applications from a country other than the United States, the Collected Information may be transferred outside of the country in which you reside or work. Your submission of the Collected Information constitutes your consent to such transfer of the Collected Information.**

**Security**                  
tyBit takes reasonable efforts to protect the security of the Collected Information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (“ **SSL** ”) software. Further, tyBit takes reasonable precautions to prevent unauthorized third parties from accessing the Collected Information stored at tyBit. Despite such efforts, hackers may wrongfully gain access to transmissions or to stored data. tyBit is not liable for damages caused by any such wrongful access. 

Email that you send us is not necessarily secure against interception. If your email communication includes sensitive information like your Social Security number, your bank account number, or your credit or charge card numbers, contact us through one of our secure online forms or by ******mail or telephone (listed below)**. 

**Contact Us**             
If you need additional information or have any questions regarding tyBit’s Privacy Policy or our Advertisers’ Privacy Policy, our technology or security, you may contact us as follows:

**Contact Information for tyBit**

·         tyBit’s Website address is:  [www.tyBit.com](http://www.tybit.com/)

The mailing address for tyBit is: tyBit, Inc., 421 Maiden Lane, Fayetteville, NC 28301.

·         **The telephone number for** tyBit **is: (** 877) 404-7250. 

·         The e-mail address to contact tyBit is:  [privacy@tyBit.com](mailto:privacy@tyBit.com)

**Latest revision date:  **This Privacy Policy was updated on 10/1/2007. Any changes made to this Privacy Policy will be effective as of the date posted to this page.
